All right. Let's get serious now. We need to move to using a real task to fetch
the weather. After all, weather is serious business. Let's
create a separate FetchWeatherTask to populate our content provider
database. And we'll start by moving our existing
task over to this new one. Wow. It's good
to get that big task out of ForecastFragment. And
we're going to change the parameters to string void, void.
Oh, we've got a lot of compile errors to fix. That's okay. For
now, we're going to delete everything except for the do in background part of
the async task. Let's give it a constructor and pass in a context.
[NOISE] In doing background, let's save off the location
query as a string to make the code easier to understand.
And for fun, let's fetch the maximum 14 days of
forecast data. Since we temporarily deleted get weather data from JSON,
we can remove from the try catch at the bottom. We're
going to look for lots of additional data from the openweather API.
To make this easy, here are the strings we'll
use. We'll also get the city name, the latitude, and
longitude returned by openweather. Now, we do have to wrap
this in a try, in order to make sure that
we handle the exception. Alright. Now we've handled the
exceptions so everything compiles. And hey look, we've got the
city name and coordinates. Hm, we've now gotten the location
that we can use to insert things into the database.
And we haven't done this in a while, so it's time for a programming exercise
but before we can do that let's actually
make sure that your app can really compile.
Let's go back to Forecast Fragment, and take a
look at how Fetch Weather Task is working. One
is that Fetch Weather Task is going to require that
we get an activity or some other context, and pass
that in there. Another thing we can do is,
remove these pesky shared preferences. And there we have
it, a utility function that gets us our preferred
location. Alright, so now, we're ready to run the applications
we can actually do the next exercise. Once again, we're going
to be calling in to our very new fetch weather task,
but it's not going to do anything but try and read some
Jason. So we want to make it do something beyond that. [SOUND]